【翻译】巴蛮子sz
Sincro: wyxchari
【时间轴】巴蛮子sz
【校对】巴蛮子sz
基于 opentitles.org 英文字幕翻译
Dalek-九号-完成
Dalek nine complete.
检查通过
Check.
(我们-是-新一代-Daleks!)
We are the new race of Daleks!
Dalek-十号-完成
Dalek ten complete.
检查通过
Check.
Dalek-十一号-完成
Dalek eleven complete.
检查通过
Check.
Dalek-十二号-完成
Dalek twelve complete.
检查通过
Check.
Dalek-十三号-通过
Dalek thirteen complete.
检查通过
Check.
Dalek-十四号-完成
Dalek fourteen complete.
检查通过
Check.
Dalek-十五号-完成
Dalek fifteen complete.
检查通过
Check.
Dalek-十六号-完成
Dalek sixteen complete.
检查通过
Check.
Dalek-十七号-完成
Dalek seventeen complete.
检查通过
Check.
Dalek-十八号-完成
Dalek eighteen complete.
怎么回事, 这是干什么?
What's the matter? What is it?
你生病了吗?
Are you ill?
它们在里面 - 制造它们自己! 在复制!
They're in there - making themselves! Duplicating!
什么? 你在说什么?
What? What are you talking about?
是我挑起的, 打开了太空舱!
I started this, opening the capsule!
Lesterson!
别想阻止我!
Don't try to stop me!
发生了什么?
What happened?
它们忘记了是该由我控制! 我重新给了它们生命复活了它们
They forget that I control them! I gave them life back again
现在我要拿走! 结束他们! 阻止它们!
And now I've taken it away! Finished! Stopped it!
那些 Daleks...
The Daleks...
邪恶! 恐怖! 我知道我要干什么了! 激光束!
Evil! Horrible! I know what I'm going to do! Laser torches!
把他们融掉! 我要把这些 Daleks 融化为金属池!
Melt them down! I'm going to melt the Daleks down to pools of metal!
你不会的 Lesterson!
You won't Lesterson!
啊, 你觉得我还顾忌你能做什么?! 去吧, 告诉每一个人是我害死了Resno!
Ah, do you think I care what you can do?!
Go on, tell everybody I was responsible for Resno's death!
我不在乎! 我要抹平这些 Daleks!
I don't care! I'm going to wipe out the Daleks!
是的, 告诉每一个人我的事. 我还是要...我要... 抹掉这些 Daleks!
Yes, tell everybody all about me! I'm still going to...
I'm going to... wipe out the Daleks!
给我接监察员. 监狱? 谁把他关进去的?
Get me the Examiner. Prison? Who put him there?
但我要跟他谈话! 我必须要, 听不懂吗?!
But I've got to talk to him! I've got to, don't you understand?!
你怎么过来的?! 我已经把电源切断了!
How did you get there?! I cut off the power!
我们-可以-储存-能量 我们-很快-会有-自己的-能量
We can store power. We will soon have our own.
自己的能量?!
Own power?!
为什么-舱门-关闭了
Why was the capsule door closed?
自己的能量?! 啊!
Own power?! Ahh!
封闭-舱体-秘密-入口
Seal off the capsule's secret entrance.
我-服从
I obey.
等!
Wait!
每次-不要-三个-以上-Daleks-同时-出现-被人-看到
No more than three Daleks to be seen together at any one time.
我-服从
I obey.
我们-还没-打算-教导-这些-人类-学习-Daleks-的法律
We are not ready yet to teach these human beings the law of the Daleks.
你可以帮我!
You can help me!
什么事情?
What's the matter?
监察员... 监察员在哪儿?! 我...
Where... where's the Examiner?! I _?!
监察员在监狱里
The Examiner's in prison.
啊, 是的
Ah, yes.
你怎么回事?
What's the matter with you?
我忘了...
I forgot.
为什么跑? 嘿!
What are you running for? Hey!
Lesterson 回来了吗?
Did Lesterson come back?
没有. 为什么-这个人-被-限制-自由?
No. Why is this human restricted?
她反对 Daleks.
She's against the Daleks.
害怕了, 是吧? 如果你乖乖地话就什么事情也没有
Afraid, are you? Nothing's going to happen to you if you behave.
Daleks? 我当然害怕 - 你也应该害怕
The Daleks? Of course I'm afraid - and so should you be.
Daleks 将要帮助我们
The Daleks are going to help us.
“我们”是指叛乱分子吧, 没说错的话
'Us' being the rebels, I suppose.
随你便.
If you like.
而且如果你们赢了的话, Daleks 会回来继续当仆人? 你们比我想的还要蠢
And when you've won, the Daleks will just go back
to being servants again? You're bigger fools than I thought.
我们-是-你们的-仆人
We are your servants.
While it suits you.
走着瞧
You'll see.
进去!
In!
你想要我留这里看着她吗?
you want me to stay with her?
是的. 你可能还得帮一下 Valmar. 他马上过来, 来修 Dalek 需要的新电缆
Yes. You may have to help Valmar. He'll be here in a minute
to fix up the new Dalek cower... power cable.
好.
Right.
什么-时候-这项-工作-完成?
When will the work be completed?
你们 Daleks 在铺设的这是什么线缆?
What is this cable you Daleks are laying, anyway?
Daleks-需要-静电-才能-运转
Daleks operate on static electricity.
静电! 这可能吗?
Static! Is that possible?
为了-制造-静电  Daleks-需要-完整的-线缆-回路
To create static, the Daleks need a complete cable circuit.
我明白了. 你把我们对我电能转换成了你们的能量
I see. You convert our electricity into your own power.
正确   什么-时候-这人-可以-完成-这项-工作?
That is correct. When will the human being complete the work?
他马上就来了. 现在比较容易了, 没有人干涉我们的计划了
He'll be here. It's easier now.
There's no-one to interfere with our plans.
你必须做这个吗? 恐怕你会发现这些锁普通人是打不开的
Do you have to do that? I'm afraid you'll find these locks are foolproof.
我很好奇他们是怎么转换能量的
I wonder how they're converting the power?
你在说什么啊...?
Wha... What are you talking about?
Daleks - 它们是依赖静电供能的, 静电就像它们的血液一样 - 一种持续的生命流
The Daleks - they're powered by static electricity.
It's like blood to them - a constant life-stream.
静电没法使用啊!
Static isn't workable!
对 Daleks 来说是可用的. 他们已经征服了静电, 正如他们征服了反磁场一样
It is to the Daleks. They've conquered static,
just as they've conquered anti-magnetics.
我不打算继续听这些胡说八道了
I'm not going to listen to any more of this nonsense.
似乎我总没法发出正确的声调
I don't seem to be able to hit the right note.
你那儿还有水吗?
Do you have any more water?
我期望没有. 没有
I hope not. No.
那我就得再搞点
Then I shall have to get some.
你没办法!
You can't!
但这很重要! 已经穷途陌路了!
But it's important! It's desperately important!
Bragen 下了命令了
Well, Bragen gave orders.
别挡我的道
Just get out of my way!
啊, 监察员, 那些 Daleks
Ah! Examiner! The Daleks...!
怎么了?
Yes?
他们在复制! 我都看见了!
They're duplicating! I've seen them!
它们现在有自己的能力了! 我没法阻止它们
They've got their own power now! I... I can't stop them!
把他带到 Bragen 那里去
Take him to Bragen.
噢... 噢... 噢...
Oh!... Oh!... Oh!...
听我说, 你觉得可否再给我们一点水?
I say. I say, do you think we might have a little more water?
你能说的就是这个? Lesterson 好不容易跑进来跟你情况, 你就只是再要一点水?
Is that all you can say? Lesterson fights his way down here
to speak to you and all you can do is demand more water?!
离门远一点
Get away from the door.
抱歉刚才发飙了, 我也是期望有所帮助
Sorry about that outburst.
I thought it might help the situation.
快了, 快了
Nearly... Nearly...
这是什么情况?
What's this?
他试图闯入监狱, 跟监察员说话
He tried to break in and speak with the Examiner.
这个 Dalek 在干什么?!
What is the Dalek doing?!
我以为你知道. 好像是应急电源什么的
I thought you knew.
Something to do with the emergency power supply.
啊, 不! 这是... 这是个伎俩! 我没有要求安装这个!
Ah, no! It's... it's a trick! I didn't ask for it!
Lesterson, 我都收到报告了.
Lesterson, I've had reports.
你在做什么?!
What are you doing?!
执行-你的-命令-铺设-应急-电源. 主人
Laying the new emergency power supply as you ordered, master.
这... 这是个谎言!
It... it... it's a lie!
我已经收到报告了, 说的就是你出现了一些不可理喻的行为
I've had reports of your incomprehensible behaviour.
是的. 是的, 我... 我能解释 - 不过你得把那东西赶开!
Yes. Yes, I... I can explain - if you'll get rid of that!
结束吧
Finish now.
我-是-你的-仆人
I am your servant.
总督在哪里?!
Where is the Governor?!
在下面巡视呢. 问这个干什么?
At the perimeter. Why?
给他打电话! 让他尽快赶回来! 我们现在处于可怕的危险当中!
Call him! Get him back here as quickly as possible!
We're all in terrible danger!
监察员是对的! 一直都是对的!
The Examiner was right! Right all the time!
别听她要说的任何话!
Don't listen to anything she has to say!
过来吧
Come along now.
她跟 Daleks 是一伙的!
She's in league with the Daleks!
现在, 现在, Lesterson. 我们冷静一点处理, 你现在看起来不太好
Now, now, now, now. Please, Lesterson.
Let's just take things calmly, you're not well.
我好得不能太好了!
I'm perfectly well!
打住 Lesterson, 打住. 现在, 你应该在医院待着. 你答应我你到那里后向我报告
Please Lesterson, please. Now, you ought to be in hospital.
You promised me you'd report there.
我才不答应这样的事情!
I promised nothing of the kind!
你难道不记得了? 算了. 我理解
Don't you remember? Never mind. I understand.
唔. 遗憾. 期望只是暂时的
Hmm. Pity. It's probably only temporary.
你是想说我疯了!
You're trying to say I'm mad!
呵呵, 不不, 不是疯了
No. No, not mad.
不是. 当然不是
No. Of course not. No.
不过我告诉你, 我看见了, Daleks 在自我复制! 我看见了! 我发誓!
But, I tell you, I saw the Daleks! They were duplicating!
I saw it! I swear to you!
他突然就开始在实验室说这些胡言乱语. 我... 我怕他是..
He suddenly started saying these things in the lab.
I'm... I'm afraid, he's...
噢, 不 ! 不!
Oh, no! No!
看住他吧.
Keep him under restraint.
噢, 没有人听进去我的话?!
Oh, will nobody listen to me?!
把那个起子递给我
Pass me that small screwdriver.
我做不到. 我的手被捆住了 .  再说了, 即使我能做到, 我也不会帮你
I can't. My hands are tied.
Anyway, I wouldn't help you, even if I could.
OK.
还有? 我都干不过来了
More? I can't handle them.
那是你的份额
This is the lot.
听.  Dalek 已经走了
Listen. The Dalek's gone now.
那并不意味着你可以说话了
That doesn't mean you can start talking.
噢, 让她一边待着, Kebble. 她不会有什么危害
Oh, leave her alone, Kebble. She isn't doing any harm.
你以为你是个硬汉吗? 不是, 也就能把一个女孩推来推去. 我倒期望你像个硬汉一样站出来
You think you're very tough don't you, pushing a girl around.
I'd like to see you come up against a real man.
比如说谁?
Like who?
比如说 Ben
Like Ben, for instance.
别替他操心了. We've got him safely stowed away. FIXME
Don't worry about him. We've got him safely stowed away.
你们抓了 Ben?
You've got Ben?
他可得好好睡一觉.
He's sleeping off a slight fall.
我跟你说了让她一边待着
I told you to leave her alone.
你的名字是 Valmar, 对吧?
Your name's Valmar, isn't it?
不假
That's it.
你想要让 Daleks 去跟总督斗。但你看不出来吗, 它们也会攻击你们的
You want the Daleks to fight the Governor.
But don't you see? They'll turn on you, too.
什么? 那三个胡椒小罐?
What? Three big pepper pots?
其中一个把 Resno 杀死了. 你们也都看到了 Dalek 对着金属板开火是什么场景
One of them did kill Resno.
You saw what the Dalek did to that sheet of metal.
而且那还只是个开始
And that's just the beginning.
别听她的, 她要把你带到监察员那个阵营
Don't listen to her. She's giving you the Examiner's line.
他不是监察员. 我们只是旅行者, 因为故障降落在这里了.
He isn't the Examiner. We're just travellers. Landed here by accident.
博士, 也就是你们以为的监察员, 他发现真正的监察员死了, 就把他的徽章捡起来了
The Doctor - that's the man you think is the Examiner
- found the real Examiner dead, and picked up his papers.
你们的这个博士, 他知道 Daleks 的一些情况?
This Doctor of yours. He knows something about the Daleks?
他试图警告每一个人. 这是我们留在这里的唯一原因
He tried to warn everyone. It's the only reason we stayed here.
什么-时候-干完-这个?
When will the work be completed?
我不知道. 我需要连接盒, 跟这个类似的
I don't know. I'll need a new junction box like this one.
你们全都低估了这些个 Daleks.
You've all underestimated these Daleks.
大脑比我们厉害, 我估计
Better brains than us, I suppose.
我只知道一些博士告诉我的 - 他说它们能够终结整个文明
I only know what the Doctor has told me
- he says they're capable of exterminating whole nations.
也许吧, 但在我们接管之后, 它们杀死我们有什么好处呢 - 我们对 Daleks一直很友好
Perhaps, but what would they want to kill us for
- after we've taken over. We're friendly with the Daleks.
但你没看出来? 人类不可能跟 Daleks 做朋友. 它们没有朋友
But, don't you see? Human beings can't be friends with Daleks.
They don't have friends.
我不明白为什么不能
I don't see why not.
它们有一种仇恨, 仇恨任何跟它们不一样的东西. 它们认为它们更高级
It's a kind of hatred for anything unlike themselves.
They think they're superior.
这女孩说的有些道理
The girl's got something.
你想要告诉 Janley 吗? 欢迎你来!
You want to tell Janley? You're welcome!
Janley! 她一有机会就会背叛你们中的大多数
Janley! She'll betray the lot of you, if she gets the chance.
另一个-连接盒-在-外面
The other junction box is outside.
谢谢你
Thank you.
太多话了, 是吧? 你不知道说到 Janley 他心肠就软了
Talk too much, don't you? Didn't you know he was soft on Janley?
没事, 没事, 我只是不想让她走向邪路.
All right, all right, I'm just putting her straight.
电缆方面我们进展太慢了
More slack on the cables.
到处布的这些都是什么线缆?
What are all these cables lying about?
新的应急供电线路
New emergency power supply.
那是谁的主意?
Who's idea was that?
你想知道这个干什么?
What do you want to know for?
我要知道...?! 你不知道我是总督?
What do I...?! Don't you know I'm the Governor?
你从哪里来的?
Where are you from?
内务部, 先生
The interior, sir.
内务部? 为什么带枪?
The interior? Why are you carrying a gun?
我是 Bragen 安保小队的队长, 先生
I'm a Squad Leader in Bragen's guard, sir.
哦, 明白了. Bragen 的保安, 嗯? 好吧, 继续拿着吧.
Oh, I see. Bragen's guard, eh? All right, carry on.
Cut that row out, 你们俩!
Cut that row out, you two!
停下.
Stop that.
噢!
Oh!
Come on.
等一下!
Wait a minute!
我可不想让他也来尝试这个方法 - 虽然他看起来也不像是个懂音调的人
We don't want him trying it,
although he seemed a bit tone deaf to me.
唉, Bragen - 这一趟趟的似乎越来越吃力了
Well, Bragen - these trips are becoming more and more demanding.
没想到你会出现, 总督
I didn't expect you, Governor.
啊, 再往外跑我就有点受不了了. 怎么样? 这里发生了什么?
Ah, I had as much as I could stand.
Well? What's been happening here?
等会儿.
One moment.
我问你问题呢, 伙计.
I asked you a question, man.
我听见了.
I heard you.
嘿, 你的工作可以先放放. 明天转交回我就行了. 我想听听监察员的情况.
Look, your work can wait. You can hand over to me tomorrow.
I want to hear about the Examiner.
监察员目前在监狱里.
The Examiner is at present in jail.
在监狱? 这样很危险, 不是吗? 谁把他投进去的?
In jail? That's rather dangerous isn't it? Who put him there?
我干的.
I did.
你干的? 天啦, 为什么?
You did? In heaven's sake, why?
他是个假冒的, 总督. 还很可能是个谋杀犯
He's an impostor, Governor. Possibly a murderer as well.
我们刚在水银沼泽里面发现了真监察员的尸体.
We have just discovered the body of the real Examiner in the mercury swamp.
我期望你说的情况都是事实, Bragen.
I hope you're sure of your facts, Bragen.
相当确定.
Quite sure.
这可能会有长远的后果.
This could have far-reaching consequences.
就我所知, 这没什么需要补充的了. 如果没有其它事情...
As far as I am concerned, there's nothing more to be said.
So if there's nothing further...
没有其它! 你以为你在跟谁说话? 跟我说话的时候站起来!
Nothing further! Who the devil do you think you're talking to?
Stand up when you're speaking to me man!
我更愿意继续坐着.
I prefer to remain seated.
是吗?! 我们就来看看. 保安!
Do you now?! We'll soon see about that. Guards!
把这个人带出我的办公室.
Take this man out of my office.
你们没有听见我说的吗? 这是命令!
Did you hear what I said? That's an order!
你忘记了, 我亲爱的 Hensell. 他们不是你的保安 - 他们是我的.
You forget, my dear Hensell. They're not your guards - they're mine.
我是总督!
I am the Governor!
不. 现在不是了. 我才是.
No. Not now. I am.
哦, 我明白了. 你的保安, 呃? 是了, Quinn 警告过我关于你的保安的事情
Oh, I see. Your guards, eh? Yes, Quinn warned me about your guards
但我们都没太重视? 不过我们很快可以纠正过来.
But we all took them too lightly, didn't we? But we'll soon change that.
你这个蠢人! 如果人们听说我在自己的首府被囚禁起来了, 你那几个保安还能自由多久?!
You imbecile! How long do you think your handful of guards can hang out
when the people hear that I am being kept a prisoner in my own capital?!
他们只会按照我们告诉他们的情况做出反应, Hensell.
The people will do exactly as they are told, Hensell.
当然, 如果你与我们合作的话, 事情会更容易一点.
It will, of course, be easier for them if you co-operate with us.
等着. 保安, 你们可以出去了.
Wait there. Guards, dismissed.
怎样, Bragen, 你需要我的合作, 对吧?
So Bragen, you want my co-operation, do you?
这样能少流些血. 我甚至可以让你继续留着总督的头衔.
It would save bloodshed.
I might even let you keep the title of Governor.
你会吗?! 我来告诉你你将会做什么. 你让你的保安都解除武装, 立即逮捕你自己!
Might you now?! I'll tell you what you will do.
You'll order your guards to disarm and place yourself under arrest immediately!
这么说你拒绝我的提议? 我还觉得在当前情形下这是个挺慷慨的提议呢.
So you reject my offer? I thought it a generous one in the circumstances.
当前什么情形?
What circumstances?
看看这个.
Look at this.
这是什么?
What is it?
这就是为什么这个基地现在是我的.
The reason that the colony is now mine.
这是某种武器?
Is it a weapon of some kind?
我给你安排一个演示吧. 你还是拒绝我的提议吗?
I'll arrange a demonstration for you. Do you still refuse my offer?
我不会妥协的.
I will not be intimidated.
当然不. 执迷不悟啊, Hensell. 杀了他!
Of course not. In character to the last, Hensell. Kill him!
为什么-人类-杀死-人类?
Why do human beings kill human beings?
去干你的活去!
Get on with your work!
是的-主人  我-服从.
Yes, master. I obey.
是的, 服从我! 从现在开始, 我要每个人都要绝对服从!
Yes, obey me! From now on,
I will have complete obedience from everyone!
现在我还得检查一下线缆回路. 否则的话, it's just as you asked for.
I'll have to check the cable circuit now.
Otherwise, it's just as you asked for.
很-好.
Very well.
为什么你们不直接利用你从基地抽取到的能量呢? 费这个劲做什么?
Why can't you carry on with the power you're drawing
from the colony? Why go to all this trouble?
到目前-为止, 我们-还是-要用-基地-电力-充电
Until now, we have had to recharge from the colony supply.
采用-静电, Daleks-将会-加倍-有用.
With static power, the Daleks will be twice as useful.
Valmar, 快点!
Valmar, quick!
怎么回事?
What's the matter?
总督回来了.
The Governor's back.
这女孩儿怎么办?
What about the girl?
别管她了.
Leave her.
我-要-跟着-你.
I will follow you.
为什么?
What for?
我-是-你的-仆人.
I am your servant.
得了吧.
Come on.
他们自己的静电供电线路! 我好奇我们还有多少时间?
An electrical circuit of their own supplying static electricity!
I wonder how much longer we've got?
我没有意识到他们将有自己的供电线路.
I didn't realise they'd have a circuit of their own.
博士, 快看!
Doctor, look out!
你没事吧?
Are you all right?
做得好! 刚才出去的那个人是谁?
Well done! Who was the man who went outside just now?
Valmar. 他一直在给 Daleks 干活.
Valmar. He's been working for the Daleks.
搭建他们的静电供应系统.
On their static power supply.
Doctor, 他们抓了 Ben.
Doctor, they've got Ben.
是的, 我知道. 他跑出来是为了让我... 噢, 这就说来话长了
Yes, I know. He ran away so that I could...
Oh well, it's a long story
不过别担心. 那小子可以照顾他自己!
But don't worry. That boy can take care of himself!
你听到了吗? That won't help.
Did you hear that? That won't help.
出去! 你们全部!
Get out! All of you!
你怎么办?!
What about you?!
但是, 博士! 噢...
But Doctor! Oh...
走!
Go!
他们-逃跑-了吗?
Have they escaped?
是的-回到-舱内-然后-报告.
Yes, return to capsule and report.
我-服从.
I obey.
我们-在-这里-等待-直到-人类-自己-内部-打起来.
We are to wait here until the human beings fight among themselves.
然后-我们-将会-攻击.
Then we will strike.
然后-终结! 终结! 终结! 终结!  ...
And exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate! ...
一个来可以救我们的人.
The one man who could have saved us.
别担心, 人们也会跟随你的.
Don't worry, the people will follow you, too.
也许吧. 但 Hensel 没有太多 there wasn't any maybe about Hensell.
Maybe. But there wasn't any maybe about Hensell.
他是个传统的人. 有点单纯, 但为这个基地做了很多了不起的工作.
He was old-fashioned. Single-minded,
yes, but he's done a lot of wonderful work for this colony.
但结果事与愿违. 为什么? 为什么他会被杀?
Events turned out against him, that's all.
But why? Why was he killed?
我能回答这个.
I can answer that.
他想要销毁 Daleks, 所以其中一个就杀死了他.
He wanted to destroy the Daleks, so one of them killed him.
现在, 我宣布戒严令. 你将返回监狱, 这次会被好好看守住.
Now, I'm declaring martial law. You will be returned to prison,
and properly guarded this time.
戒严令! 你觉得这对于对付 Daleks 有什么作用?
Martial law! What good do you think that will do against the Daleks?
Daleks 会听命于我
The Daleks will do as I tell them.
那我们就看看吧, 看吧
We shall see, shan't we.
把他们带走.
Take them away.
终结 ! 终结 ! 终结 !
Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate!
指令-已收到. 终结所有人类!
Orders received. Exterminate all humans!
终结所有人类!
Exterminate all humans!
终结 ! 灭绝! 摧毁 ! Daleks-征服-并摧毁!
Exterminate! Annihilate! Destroy! Daleks conquer and destroy!